Guide to the Arturo Islas Papers, 1956-1991
Department of Special Collections
- Series 5: Subject Files
  - James, Henry: lectures: Henry James: North Americas's Aristocrat, Henry James's Washington Square, An Ugly Duckling Story, `Daisy Miller,' `The Turn of the Screw;' Two Women Done in by Propriety, On Portrait of a Lady, Perfect Henry James: The Ambassadors and the `Helpless Jelly,' Washington Square, Henry James; more Introductory Remarks, notes, paper - The Apotheosis of Appearance in The Golden Bowl (1961),booklet - Henry James in Northhampton (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Kafka, Franz: notes, magazine articles, lecture (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Lawrence, D. H. (1975):notes and lectures on Women In Love (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Levertov, Denise (1961-1987):correspondence, news clippings, photograph, notes and letters from Islas (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Levertov, Denise (1987):correspondence, news clippings, photograph, booklet: El Salvador: Requiem, introductory speech for Levertov by Islas (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Modern American Literature: class notes (fall 1964),essay (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Mailer, Norman: notes, lectures: On Norman Mailer's Prisoner of Sex, On An American Dream (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - McCullers, Carson: lecture: Carson McCullers; Another Perpetual Wedding Guest (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Melville, Norman: notes, lecture: Herman Melville; North America's Shakespeare (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Nabokov, Vladimir: letter to Islas (1967),lectures: Vladimir Nabokov, Lolita (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Norris, Frank (1977):lectures: Frank Norris's McTeague, Frank Norris (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - O'Connor, Flannery (1959-):notes, lectures, including Flannery O'Connor's Wise Blood; A Grimly Comic Book (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Orwell: Politics and the English Language (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Paz, Octavio: lecture, news clippings (1979) (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Porter, K. A.: notes and lectures (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Proust and James (Winter 1984):notes, magazine clippings (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Robinson, E. A.: lecture (1972) (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Shaksespeare: class notes (1964),student paper: Morality in King Lear (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Stevens, Wallace: notes (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Tolstoy: lectures, news clipping (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Twain, Mark: notes, news, and magazine articles on Twain, lectures: Samuel Clemens/Mark Twain (1835-1910):Two-Sided Man, The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn: A Chronicle of Child Abuse, paper - Limited Authors, Realistic Angels, and the Quality of Detachment (1958) (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Wharton, Edith: notes and lecture (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Whitman, Walt: poetry, notes, lecture (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Adams House Seminar: Shrapnel Love memo (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - American Fiction Between the Wars (1979)course abstract (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - American Studies: minutes from meeting (1975),list of courses (1981-82),memos (1971) (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Interdisciplinary Seminar - Chicano Culture (1989):syllabus, student work, xeroxed readings (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Masterpieces of American Literature (Autumn 1988-1989):class handouts, notes, lectures: Introductions to Some Masterpieces..., Concluding Remarks in Masterpieces... course (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Continuing Education: letter form Bill Chace (1987) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - English 162B (Autumn 1987-88) -Creative Writing for Bilingual Students: syllabus, news clipping: Is Fiction the Art of Lying? (1984) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Courses, Ideas, and Values (1988-1989):memos, CIV Program Committee info, CIV track syllabus (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Masterpiece of American Literature (Winter 1985-1986):class handouts and notes (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - American Literature, 1855-1917 (Winter 1979)notes (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Masterpieces of American Literature (Autumn 1984-85):notes, class handouts (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Masterpieces of American Literature (Winter 1983)class handout (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - 356B Autobiography Seminar/ UTEP (Autumn 1986):memos, student papers, xeroxed articles, class notes (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Advanced Fiction Writing (Spring 1987),UTEP: news clippings, class notes, news articles, correspondence (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Fitzgerald/English (Spring 1987),UTEP: class handouts, student paper (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Fiction Writing (Fall 1986),UTEP: news clipping and short stories, class handouts, notes (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - UTEP/ spring semester syllabi (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - UTEP (1985-1988):correspondence, office memos, news clipping (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Masculine/Feminine in Fiction (1974-1975):class handout, letter to D. Middlebrook, articles, lectures (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - English 122: American Literature, 1855-1917 (Winter 1981-82):class handout, notes, student work, memos from students (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - English 122 (1972):class handouts and notes (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Curriculum Committee (1979):time schedule, office memos (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Freshman Seminar (Autumn 1980-81)class notes (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Freshman Seminar (Winter 1980-81) (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Freshman Seminar (Autumn 1983-84/Summer 1984):notes, memos, handouts (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Santa Cruz: correspondence and course information (1975) (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Women: bibliography of books about women (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Romance Heroine: lectures - untitled (n.d.)and Romance and Romance Heroines in America, student paper (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Puritans: notes (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Pachucos: The Pachuco Patois, Beatrice Griffin and Pachuco: An American-Spanish Argot (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - English 45 (1983):student papers, memos, handouts (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - English 45 (Spring 1984):final exam and class evaluations (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - English 45 (Spring 1980-81) (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - American Lives Seminar (winter 1980-1981):student papers, notes from students, class handouts (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - American Lives (1981-1982):student work, course evaluations (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - American Lives (Winter 1984):notes, class handouts, xerox readings (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - American Lives (Winter 1985):student work, notes from students (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - American Lives (Summer 1986):class handout, notes from students (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - American Lives (1988):course evaluations, notes, syllabi (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - American Lives Evaluations (Winter 1989-1990) (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - American Lives - Student works: collections of student essays from Winter 1980-81 and Winter 1985 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - American Lives - Student Work and Correspondence, etc. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Course Evaluations (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Chicano Literature Course Evaluations (Spring 1990) (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Chicano Literature Course Evaluations (Autumn 1989) (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Fitzgerald and Hemingway Course Evaluations (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - American Literature Course Evaluations (Autumn 1988) (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Movie Reviews (1965-1971):entertainment reviews (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - El Paso Authors (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Education (1966-1968):student papers, work by Islas (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Poetry: collected poetry (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Machismo, Masculinity, and Male Love (1975-1977):magazine and news clippings (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Psychic Phenomena (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Sexuality (1964-1971):news clippings and articles (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Franklin (Prof. Bruce Franklin, 1971):office memos, Campus Report (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Recommendation letters (1973) (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - English 9, Fall 1971 (1958-1979):notes, handouts, syllabi (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - English 20 (Fall 1972):lectures, finals, student papers (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Chace English 179, Spring 1971 (1971-1972):notes, class handouts (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - American Program Bureau: correspondence, misc. papers (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - California Association of Teachers of English (1987-1988):news articles, address to California State Teachers of English Conference (Feb. 12, 1988),CATE convention info, correspondence (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - CCCTE Conference: Asilomar 40 conference information (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - CCCC/NCTE (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Chicano Conference, Stanford, May 1987 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Cinco Puntos Press: correspondence (1980) (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Jean Coblentz Book Club (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Compton Danforth (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - DIA, Americas Society, NY, May 1990(Latin American Writer's Conference and the DIA Arts Foundation): speeches, notes, outgoing memo, correspondence (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Guadalupe Cultural Arts Center: incoming and outgoing correspondence (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - In These Times Western Journal of Medicine (1990)incoming and outgoing correspondence (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Latin American Conference, Long Beach, April 1990 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - RETE newsletter (August 1990):Raza Educators Teaching English (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - RMMLA, 1987, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - RMMLA, 1989:incoming and outgoing correspondence (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Sacred Heart Prep Talk (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Senior Learning Center (1983-1990):letters, brochures (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Southwest Book Award (1986):incoming and outgoing correspondence, news articles, photocopy of the award (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Story Line Press (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Summer Conference Lilly Renewal (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Texas Library Association [Intellectual Freedom Committee] (1988):news clippings, incoming correspondence, publications (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - UCLA (Dec. 1989)Reading: Avocado/ Chakespeare Louie (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Writer's Conference, Los Altos (1990):news clipping, letter, thank you letters from students (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Speeches and Articles: Los Angelses Alumni Conference Talk (1990),2 untitled (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Public Presentations: announcements, letters, news clippings (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Readings (1986-1988) (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Islas Collection at Stanford: correspondence (1985, 1986) (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Promotion Papers to Full Professor (1985-1986):correspondence, news clipping (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Advisory Committee Centennial Campaign (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Afro-American Search Committee (1988-1989) (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Committee (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Club (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Seminar (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Galarza Lecture (May 18, 1990):incoming and outgoing correspondence, lecture - On the Bridge, At the Border: Migrants and Immigrants, excerpt from Migrant Souls - The Middle of Nowhere (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Graduate Studies Committee (1989-1990) (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Stanford HELP Center (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Modern Thought and Literature Committee in Charge (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - University Fellows (1979-1980):Presentation to the University Fellows and visiting administrators on the theme of undergraduate education and its relations to minorities at Stanford (Oct. 25, 1979) (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Dinkelspiel Award (1976):news clippings, commencement booklet (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Senior Class Day (1984-1985):Senior Class Day Address (June 16, 1984),news clippings, correspondence, fliers, 93rd Annual Commencement/1984 booklet, Chicano Graduation Address (June 16, 1985) (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Senior Class Day (1988):news clippings, memos, speech (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Class Day (1990):speech, incoming correspondence, memos (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Women's Club (San Francisco 1982):memos and speeches (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Stanford Sierra Camp (1984, 1986) (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Stanford Class Reunion (1985):speech (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Parents Day 1987:speech (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Talk to Freshman class: speech (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Grant Applications/Proposals (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Howard Foundation: memos and invoices (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Whiting Foundation (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Richard Rodriguez - Correspondence (1982-1987):responses to Islas's article on Rodriguez (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Richard Rodriguez - Islas's Articles (1982-1985):book review of Hungry of Memory by R. Rodriguez, incoming letters, notes, article - Nobody's Victim: the `Scholarship Boy' as Writer (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Richard Rodriguez - Articles: by Jose Antonio Burciaga, Paul Skenazy, and Richard Rodriguez (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Richard Rodriguez (1982-1987):reviews of R. Rodriguez and articles on affirmative action (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Danny Santiago (news articles and reviews): news articles, and reviews (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Danny Santiago correspondence (1983-1984):incoming and outging correspondence (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Hunger of Memory: The Education of Richard Rodriguez: uncorrected proof (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - My Name Will Follow You Home by Danny Santiago: uncorrected proof (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Chicano Fellows (1971-1974):news letters, memos (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Chicano Graduate Associat: proposals, policy, memos (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Lecture notes on Acosta, Anaya, Castaneda, Rivera, Valdez, Villarreal (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Bicultural Styles, Freshman English (Spring 1975)handouts (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Chicano Literature - Writing Section (Fall 1974) (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Chicano Literature 62/62W (Autumn 1974):class handouts, journal article - The Making of a Legend by Elroy Bode (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Chicano Literature, English 162 (Autumn 1975):class handouts, student work (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Chicano Literature (Autumn 1980-1981):notes and syllabi (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Chicano Culture (Spring 1979-1980):old exams (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Bilingual Education news clippings (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Cesar Chavez and the United Farm Workers: fliers (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - New Voices in Literature: The Mexican American - a symposium (Oct 7-8, 1971)booklet (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Chicano Bibliography (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Articles on Chicanos (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Chicano Lecture (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Chicano Material (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Chicano Literature (Winter Quarter, 1971)outgoing letter, memo, student poetry (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Chicano Publishing Houses: pamphlets, articles, letters (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Sandra Cisneros: incoming and outgoing correspondences, resume (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Conferences (1974):letters and information on the Social Sciences and Humanities Workshop de la Experiencia Chicana and Modern Language Association of America (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Mexicans and Chicanos: news clippings (1972-1974)and Mexico, Latin America, and the Spanish Southwest Catalogue (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Contemporary Mexican Writers (1974-1975):syllabi, notes, lectures, news articles (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Mexico in American and British Letters bibliography (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Mexican Revolution bibliography (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - MIQUIZTLI (1974-1975):lectures, correspondence, news clippings (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Mexican Studies Program: proposals and memos (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Luis L. Arroyo (1982):correspondence and resume (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Chicano Culture (1979-1980):class handouts, notes (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Chicano Culture: notes, essays by others, Saints, Artists, and Vile Politics... manuscript, syllabus (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Chicano Faculty (1974-1975):proposals, reports (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Chicano Faculty (1981-1982)memos (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Potential Chicano Faculty Candidates: lists and resumes (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Chicano Fellows Organization (1971-1982):memos, reports, questionnaire, general information (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Chicano Fellows (1981-1982)memos and minutes (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Chicano Fellows (1979-1980)meeting minutes, notes, memos, bulletins, newsletters (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Chicano Studies Center (1976-1980):memos, reports, correspondence (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Ethnic Studies Berkeley (1979):incoming letter of correspondence (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Affirmative Action (Spring 1981):memos, faculty affirmative action report (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Affirtmative Action University Committee (1981-1982)correspondence (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Renewal (Summer 1982):office memos, notes, info (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Interdisciplinary Seminar (Autumn 1979-1980):photocopies of readings, notes, correspondence (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Interdisciplinary Seminar (Autumn 1979-1980):photocopies of essays, articles, poems, songs on Chicano literature (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Interdisciplinary Seminar: photocopies of Chicano literature (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - English 380 (Autumn 1981-1982)Interdisciplinary Seminar: course info, photocopied essays and articles on Chicano issues (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Center for Chicano Research (SCCR, 1982-1983):correspondence and memos (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - SCCR Projects (1982-1983):project information and proposals (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Spanish Department (Manuel de Jesus Hernandez): letters of recomendation for Hernandez, manuscripts for Hernandez (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Spanish Department (1981-1982)memos (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - U.S./Mexico conference, Spring 1980 (1979-1980):lecture - The Intellectual and Public Life, memos, and conference information (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Chicano Fellows (1987-1989):resumes, memos, correspondence, meeting minutes, proposals] (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Chicano Graduate Students Association (1988):newsletter and roster (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Micheal M. J. Fischer: essay - Ethnicity and the PostModern Arts of Memory (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Minority Education (1986-1987):articles (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Chicano Issues (1973-1987):articles and news clippings (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Journals and Newsletters on Pluralism and Chicano Issues: Plural (June-Oct. 1987),In Writing (Vol. 5 No. 1, Winter 1988),Stanford Observer (April 1989),La Onda (Oct.-Nov. 1975),Carta Abierta (1987),Imagenes de la Chicana (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Lists of Chicano Literature (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Center for Chicano Research reports (1983-1988) (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Chicano Collections: Stanford University Libraries bibliography (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Chicano literature: photocopied readings (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Chicano writings: photocopied readings - essays, fiction (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Chicano Journals (1972-1990):Bovine Interventions (1990),Hispanorama (1990),Miquiztli (Vol. Issue 1, Fall 1972),Miquiztli (Vol. 2, Issue 1, Winter Quarter 1974),Miquiztli (Vol. 3, Issue 1, Winter-Spring, 1975) (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Ernesto Galarza Commerative Lectures (1986, 1987, 1990)with memo from Tony Burciaga (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - News Clippings: Chicano Issues (1983-1988) (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - News Clippings: Homosexuality (1983-1987) (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - News Clippings: Miscellaneous (1972-1989) (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, etc. - inscribed by authors with notes to Islas (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Miscellany: photocopied articles and fliers (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Excerpts from New Scholar (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Articles on Chicano culture (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Excerpts from Aztlan (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - El Paso Times, 1978 -news clippings (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Cortes - Mexican Americans (Box 38, Folder 10)
- Series 6: People Files
  - Mailing List (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - John Ashberry (1973-1976):news clipping, incoming correspondence (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Margaret Barrett (1974-1976):incoming correspondence (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Arvin Brown: article on Brown - He Trusts Plays, He Trusts Actors, New York Times (Oct. 12, 1975),Performing Arts magazine (Feb. 1974/Vol. 8, No. 2) (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Gil Carbajal (1974-1976):incoming correspondence (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Bill Chace: A Good Marxist Liberal, Stanford Daily (Dec. 3, 1979),letter (1975),and publications by Chace (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Norma Djerassi: correspondence (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - John Felstiner: publications and writings (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Dame Margot Fonteyn: memo, complimentary ticket, news clippings (1975-1976) (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Albert Guerard: autographed xeroxed copies of Guerard's essays (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Maclin Bocock Guerard: photocopied short stories (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Ethel Hoffman (1874-1976):incoming correspondence (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Betsy Jablon: letter (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Stina Katchadourian: correspondence (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Runa Lindfors Nunni: incoming correspondence (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Harry Matthews: incoming letter (May 20, 1974) (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Meyer, Lillie, & Arthur: profile of the Arthurs (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Anne K. Mellor: publications by Mellor (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Diane Middlebrook: poetry, literary work, correspondence (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Gail Mortimer (1984):note and Description of Proposed Study (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Joe O'Mealy (1975-1976):incoming correspondence (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Renato Rosaldo (1972-1976):incoming correspondence, writings (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Wallace Stegner: incoming correspondence, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Ian Watt: book review (1970),incoming correspondence (1975-1976),publications (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Articles by Colleagues (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Hector Calderon (1985-1986):incoming and outgoing correspondence (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Robert Cantu (1989):incoming correspondence, copies of entry Arturo Islas for Dictionary of Literary Biography, Chicano Authors, Second Series (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Denise Chavez (1987-1990):letters (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Bliss Carnochan: published articles (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Norm Dichotsky: letters and publications (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Jim English (1983-1990):correspondence, letter of recommendation, papers by English, curriculum vitae, oral exam for Ph. D. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Pat Geuder (1989-1990):incoming correspondence (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Mimi Reisel Gladstein (1987):letter of recommendation and curriculum vitae (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Jose Limon (1990):memo, curriculum vitae (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Geoff Loftus (1987-1989)correspondence (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Carolyn Lougee (1985):memos, statement for Approaching Stanford, Stanford Then and Now, Parents Day Speech (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Bill Nerricio (1989):writings, curriculum vitae, letter of recommendation, correspondence (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - [UNK] Padilla (1983-1984):writings, correspondence, letter of recomendation (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Americo Paredes: writings (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Wayne Pounds: Hawthorne and Samuel P. Newmann: Rhetoric's Iron Cage (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Tomas Rivera (1975):incoming and outgoing correspondence, notes, news clippings (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Marta Sanchez (1989):outgoing letter, Arturo Islas' Rain God: An Alternative Tradition (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Edward Simmon (1989-1990):correspondence (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Robert Trujillo (1982):correspondence (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Yvonne Yarbo-Bejarano: correspondence, curriculum vitae, The Female Subject in Chicano Theater: Sexuality, Race, and Class (Dec. 1986) (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Tomas Ybarra-Frausto (1983-1990):correspondence and letter of recommendation (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Lisa DeBrito (1985)letter (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Pat Geuder: curriculum vitae, correspondence, letter of recommendation, application of sabbatical leave (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Dagoberto Gilb (1987):correspondence and short stories (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - J. Jason Hammer-Acevedo (1990):incoming and outgoing correspondence (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - HI Books: letter (1989) (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - David Holdaway (1985):incoming and outgoing correspondence and photo (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Stuart Klawans (1986):incoming and outgoing correspondence, article - The Small Time from Our Nation (Box 41, Folder 7)